nikontech.com 2012-06-09

# Nikon Privacy Policy

_Effective December 22, 2010_   

1\. Our Commitment to Privacy  
2\. Sites Covered by This Privacy Policy   
3\. The Information We Collect   
4\. How We Use Collected Information   
5\. Who We Share Information With  
6\. Links to Non-Nikon Owned Sites  
7\. Our Commitment to Information Security   
8\. Our Commitment to Children's Privacy   
9\. How to Access or Update Your Information   
10\. Your Privacy Preferences Regarding Personally Identifiable Information—Opting In/Out   
11\. Changes in Policy   
12\. How to Contact Us 

**1\. Our Commitment to Privacy:  
** Nikon Inc. ("NIKON”, “we” “our” or “us”) recognizes that the protection of personal information that it receives from visitors of its websites is very important. Collecting information allows NIKON to develop and maintain websites that enable us to better understand and to be more responsive to you as well as assisting us in managing our business better. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.  

**2\. Sites Covered by This Privacy Policy  
** This privacy policy applies to the following NIKON owned websites:  
[nikonusa.com](http://www.nikonusa.com/);  
[support.nikonusa.com](http://support.nikonusa.com/);  
[ashton.nikonusa.com](http://ashton.nikonusa.com/);  
[nikonpro.com](http://nikonpro.com/);  
[nikonsportoptics.com](http://nikonsportoptics.com/);  
[nikonhunting.com](http://nikonhunting.com/);   
[nikonbirding.com](http://nikonbirding.com/);  
(collectively "Nikon Owned Websites"). 

**3\. The Information We Collect:**   
By visiting any of our NIKON Owned Websites, we collect non-personally identifiable information about you, and we may also collect personally identifiable information that you provide to us. 

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information** is information that cannot be used to identify you or to contact you and is information not associated with a specific personal identity. It is information that we collect automatically from you by tracking your use of our NIKON Owned Websites by using technology and methodology that enables tracking, such as the use of cookies, and includes but is not limited to information, such as domain type, browser version, service provider, internet protocol address, time spent and pages visited on our NIKON Owned Websites as well as information searched for on our NIKON Owned Websites. A “cookie” is a small file that a website transfers to the hard drive of a visitor’s computer for record keeping purposes. This tracking through the use of cookies will not by itself reveal anything to us about you personally or provide us with any information that personally identifies you, such as your name, e-mail address or other personally identifiable information. Non-personally identifiable information is also information that you, at your option, voluntarily provide us while you are visiting one of our NIKON Owned Websites and includes but is not limited to information such as your hobbies and interests, gender, age, level of education, photographic skill level as well as your purchases of and your experience with our products. 

**Personally Identifiable Information** is information that is associated with a person’s name or personal identity and can be used to identify or contact you. It includes but is not limited to such information as your name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, and credit/debit card information. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen (13). 

**4.  How We Use Collected Information  
**NIKON uses collected information to help us better understand your needs and interests so that we may provide you with better service. Specifically, we use personally identifiable information to help you complete a transaction or order with us, to respond to your inquiries and requests, to provide and update you on our customer services and support, to notify you of promotional or special offers, to communicate with you about our products and services, and to allow you to participate in an interactive feature. (See Section 10 below, “Your Privacy Preferences Regarding Personally Identifiable Information-Opting In/Out” regarding communications to you.) Personally identifiable information in the form of credit/debit card information is used only for payment processing and fraud prevention. We use non-personally identifiable information to increase the functionality and user friendliness of our NIKON Owned Websites as well as to improve the design, content and user experience of all of our NIKON Owned Websites. We may also use non-personally identifiable information for research purposes such as analyzing how visitors use and navigate our NIKON Owned Websites. In addition, we may take your personally identifiable information and make it non-personally identifiable, either by combining it with information about other individuals (aggregating your information with information about other individuals), or by removing characteristics, such as your name, that make the information personally identifiable to you, i.e., de-personalizing your information. Given the nature of this information, there are no restrictions under this privacy policy upon NIKON’s right to aggregate or de-personalize your personal identifiable information, and use and/or share with third parties the resulting non-personally identifiable information in any way.   

**5\. Who We Share Information With**  
NIKON does not sell, rent or lease any of your personally identifiable information to third parties. NIKON also does not share your personally identifiable information with third parties except we may disclose personally identifiable information to companies affiliated with NIKON, such as our parent company, and/or unaffiliated third parties working on our behalf or for us or with us, such as agents, vendors and suppliers, but only for the purpose to enable them to fulfill your requests to us for product, services or information. All such affiliated and unaffiliated parties who have access to personally identifiable information are required to keep confidential such information and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for NIKON and as otherwise required by law. Except as otherwise stated in this policy, NIKON will not share personally identifiable information with third parties without your permission, unless to (a) comply with any law, subpoena, regulation or court order; (b) respond to requests from governmental authorities; or (c) help prevent fraud or to protect the safety, rights, property or security of NIKON as well as that of third parties. 

**6\. Links to Non-Nikon Owned Sites  
** NIKON Owned Websites may provide links to other websites which are not owned by NIKON and are owned by companies or parties which are either affiliated or unaffiliated with NIKON (“Non-NIKON Owned Websites”). These links to Non-NIKON Owned Websites are provided to you as a matter of convenience and for informational purposes. If you access any of these links, you will no longer be on a NIKON Owned Website. We do not endorse or make any representations about Non-NIKON Owned Websites, and we are not responsible for and we disclaim all warranties, express or implied, as to the privacy, content or security of such Non-NIKON Owned Websites. You are responsible for reviewing, and we encourage you to review the policies including the privacy policy of such Non-NIKON Owned Websites. 

**7\. Our Commitment To Information Security**   
Information security is important at NIKON, and while no security measure is perfect or impenetrable and we cannot guarantee the security of the information that you provide to us, you can be assured that we maintain physical, electronic and administrative measures and safeguards and periodically review these security measures and safeguards to protect your personally identifiable information from unauthorized or inappropriate access and use.  

**8\. Our Commitment To Children's Privacy**   
Our NIKON Owned Websites are not directed at children, and we do not knowingly solicit or collect personal information from or about children under the age of thirteen (13). Should any parent or guardian discover that his/her child has provided personal information to NIKON, please e-mail [webmaster@nikon.net](mailto:webmaster@nikon.net) to have such information deleted from our records.  

**9\. How To Access or Update Your Information  
** You can access, edit, delete and update any personally identifiable information that you provided to us through our NIKON Owned Websites and that we maintain, by visiting [Nikon Knowledge Database](http://support.nikontech.com/cgi-bin/nikonusa.cfg/php/enduser/acct_login.php?p_sid=uBfgtpZi&p_accessibility=0&p_redirect=&p_lva=&p_sp=cF9zcmNoPSZwX3NvcnRfYnk9JnBfZ3JpZHNvcnQ9JnBfcm93X2NudD0xMjI5LDEyMjkmcF9wcm9kcz0mcF9jYXRzPSZwX3B2PSZwX2N2PSZwX3NlYXJjaF90eXBlPWFuc3dlcnMuc2VhcmNoX25sJnBfcGFnZT0x&p_next_page=myovr.php&p_li=).  We use this procedure to better safeguard your personally identifiable information.  

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take steps to verify your identity before granting you access to edit or update your personally identifiable information.  

**10\. Your Privacy Preferences Regarding Personally Identifiable Information-Opting In /Out  
**NIKON will not use your personally identifiable information for purpose(s) other than the purpose(s) for which you provided it to us. What this means is that NIKON will not send you information about NIKON products, services, promotions, events, firmware or software updates, and service advisories as well as how to get more enjoyment from your NIKON products and photography unless you request them. You can request them by contacting us at [Nikon Email Updates](http://www.nikonusa.com/fileuploads/html/optinform.html) or by opting in at the appropriate website location. In addition, in the event you no longer wish to receive information that you previously requested, you may opt out by contacting us at [Nikon Email Preferences](http://support.nikontech.com/cgi-bin/nikonusa.cfg/php/enduser/doc_serve.php?2=eof).  

**11\. Changes in Policy**  
By visiting any of our NIKON Owned Websites, you consent to our collection and use of your information as set forth in this policy. NIKON reserves the right to modify or supplement this privacy policy, including our collection and use and related business practices, at any time by posting updated text on our NIKON Owned Websites. Changes to this privacy policy are effective at the time they are posted to our NIKON Owned Websites.  For this reason, it is your responsibility and NIKON encourages you to review this privacy policy each time you visit any of our NIKON Owned Websites.  

**12\. How To Contact Us**   
If you have any questions, comments or concerns with respect to our privacy practices or this privacy policy statement, please feel free to contact us at [webmaster@nikon.net](mailto:webmaster@nikon.net).    

Back to Top
